{
    "id": "61bf11df517b44199aca6a543fb4f4ab",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I knew why I ………………………..",
            "description": "We use a past perfect (passive) here because the main verb is in the past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "have chosen",
                "have been chosen",
                "had been chosen"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "7b861689cfc340b38cef4b0b6334ad44"
        },
        {
            "question": "My life …………………………. by that book.",
            "description": "We use the passive form of the simple past here because the subject is not the doer of the action.",
            "answers": [
                "changed",
                "has changed",
                "was changed"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "5d9254f8d0244346898f4c869c2a08fb"
        },
        {
            "question": "A friend of ours ………………………….. the roof.",
            "description": "The present continuous is used here because we are talking about an ongoing situation.",
            "answers": [
                "repairs",
                "is repairing",
                "is being repaired"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e6f5431efbf34f0dbc80313c982e4bcf"
        },
        {
            "question": "You will be called when your time ………………………….",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the future tense, we use a present tense in the subordinate clause to refer to future.",
            "answers": [
                "come",
                "comes",
                "will come"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1983d84f659a4ef395d07e41f556c60f"
        },
        {
            "question": "Young babies need to …………………………",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "take care of",
                "be taken care of"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "cc9f0791814b46ae979acbbacf82f051"
        },
        {
            "question": "She ……………………………. a bath when she heard a knock on the door.",
            "description": "The past continuous is used to talk about the longer background action that was going on when another action took place.",
            "answers": [
                "had",
                "was having",
                "had had"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "aae52083459f40e0befbcfbe04a8f29c"
        },
        {
            "question": "They ………………………………. by the immigration officer.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "questioned",
                "are being questioned",
                "are questioning"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "90045103bfbe4e41babba0e6b42fb43c"
        },
        {
            "question": "This color …………………………… me.",
            "description": "We use the simple present to talk about facts.",
            "answers": [
                "is not suiting",
                "does not suit"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c4a08ff5324b4a3a8734495c4b76b76a"
        },
        {
            "question": "She ………………………….. her mother.",
            "description": "We use the simple present to talk about facts, truths etc.",
            "answers": [
                "resembles",
                "is resembling"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "27d19c32fd0147eab03c36700cdb42ca"
        },
        {
            "question": "These carpets ………………………… by child workers in Asia.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "made",
                "have made",
                "are made"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "49de04205d5c4424b0f58cb659fbb39e"
        },
        {
            "question": "You …………………………… five thousand dollars last year.",
            "description": "Were lent is the passive form of lent.",
            "answers": [
                "were lent",
                "lend",
                "have lent"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "7f584b757f524749abc71b53f4a45cf6"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ……………………….. an invitation.",
            "description": "Was sent is the passive form of sent. ",
            "answers": [
                "send",
                "was sent",
                ""
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "59197df5700343ebb05f5d31b05a23c4"
        }
    ]
}